Hello everyone and welcome
to EnglishPod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine and
it's the holiday season today.
We have a lesson all about
a special December holiday.
That's right.
We are getting close to
Christmas and of course
today we are going
to talk about Christmas
in the United States and some of the
typical traditions that you see over there.
That's right.
So we're going to be looking at a family as
they wait for Christmas morning to arrive.
If you don't know
what that is, don't worry.
You'll hear us talk about it in a moment,
but first let's listen to our dialogue.
What are you doing awake?
I can't sleep, but it's almost midnight.
Exactly.
I'm too excited for Christmas morning.
Also, I thought I heard Santa.
Really?
How do you know it was Santa?
Well, I heard that naughty boys and
girls get cold and they're stockings.
So I thought I'd be nice
and make Santa cookies.
I even left out some milk.
I heard someone in the kitchen
eating the cookies, so I came downstairs.
Hmm.
Well, I know that Santa
won't come down the
chimney with you hiding
behind the tree spying on him.
Really?
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
That way we can let Santa do his job.
Then, when you wake up,
it will be Christmas already.
Okay.
Hey, honey, is that you?
Don't eat all the cookies.
I want some, too.
All right, we're back.
So now let's take a look at some
language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Okay, I just said it, but here's that
phrase again, Christmas morning.
That's right.
So Christmas morning is
December 25th in the morning, right?
That's right.
Okay, so the tradition
is that small children
will wake up early
and run downstairs and
they will find Christmas
presents under the Christmas tree.
And so this is the
Christmas morning tradition.
Okay.
In many countries, they celebrate Christmas
on Christmas Eve, the 24th, right?
All right.
So Christmas Eve is
December 24th, Christmas
day, or if it's in the morning,
Christmas morning is December 25th.
And as you said, kids come downstairs or
go to where the Christmas tree is to look
for their presents that Santa
came in and left for them.
That's right.
So the idea, the story is
that Santa comes at night
late at night and brings
presents for the children.
And when the children wake up, they see
the presents, but Santa has already gone.
So Santa is a man.
He's kind of a mythical figure with a big
white beard and a red outfit and a red hat.
Right.
So his name is Santa Claus or just Santa.
There are many, many
different names for Santa
different cultures
in different countries.
Yeah.
Some people like to
call him Saint Nick or
Saint Nicholas, but most people
will call him Santa in America.
That's right.
So this is what happens,
part of what happens
during Christmas
Eve and Christmas day.
And usually also boys
and girls will find our
stockings that will be filled
with candy or small toys as well.
That's right.
There are basically
socks, but these are special
socks that you don't
wear, you hang them.
And a lot of people
like to put them on the
fireplace, they hang
them from the fireplace.
And like you said, Marco,
they're filled with sweets.
The story says that boys and girls who are
nice get good things like sweets and toys
and boys and girls who
are naughty get cold.
Cold.
So that's that black material that we
use to make a barbecue, for example.
Yeah, exactly.
It's very dirty and it's not
something you want in your stocking.
Okay.
That's right.
So that's what we get in our stockings.
And now when the
small boy and his father
were talking, they were
saying that, you know,
he should go back to bed
and not hide behind the tree.
So if they're in the
living room or they're
downstairs in the house,
what tree do they have?
We're not talking about
a big real tree outside.
We're talking about the Christmas tree.
But you know, it's a long
phrase, the Christmas tree.
We don't have to say it that way.
When we have a Christmas tree inside
the house, we can just call it the tree.
Okay.
And a Christmas tree,
as many of you may
have seen already, is
a pine tree usually and
you put decorations on it
and the presents go under it.
That's right.
So you might hear
this phrase, there are
presents under the tree
or there are many nice
presents under the tree.
That means there are lots of nice
presents under the Christmas tree.
That's right.
Well, the kid wanted to stay behind
the tree and spy on Santa Claus.
That's right.
So this is a verb to spy.
This means to watch
someone, but to watch them
while they don't know
that you're watching them.
So you're hiding, but
looking at someone else.
Right.
You're spying.
This is where the, the, the noun
comes a spy like James Bond.
James Bond spy, he is a very famous spy.
That's right.
The boy does not want Santa Claus to
see him, so he is spying on Santa Claus.
All right.
Very good stuff.
Why don't we listen to the
dialogue again and review this vocab.
What are you doing awake?
I can't sleep, but it's almost midnight.
Exactly.
I'm too excited for Christmas morning.
Also, I thought I heard Santa.
Really?
How do you know it was Santa?
Well, I heard that
naughty boys and girls
get cold and they're stockings, so I
thought I'd be nice and make Santa cookies.
I even left out some milk.
I heard someone in the kitchen
eating the cookies, so I came downstairs.
Hmm.
Well, I know that Santa
won't come down the
chimney with you hiding
behind the tree, spying on him.
Really?
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
That way we can let Santa do his job.
Then when you wake up,
it will be Christmas already.
Okay.
Hey, honey, is that you?
Don't eat all the cookies.
I want some too.
All right.
We're back.
So now let's take a look at
three phrases on fluency builder.
Fluency builder.
All right.
So Marco, there's another great
phrase in here that we often use to run.
Christmas.
What is it that Santa Claus does?
Well, the way Santa
Claus leaves presents
for boys and girls is that he
will come down the chimney.
And we saw that when
the dad said, well, Santa
Claus won't come down the chimney
if you're here hiding behind the tree.
All right.
So the chimney is part of the fireplace.
Fireplaces where you have a
fire in your house to keep warm.
And the chimney is where the
smoke goes to come outside.
But Santa Claus goes
the other way he comes
down the chimney from
the roof into your house.
That's right.
And then he leaves the presents.
So the father said, all right.
So you know, stop spying on Santa.
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
All right.
Get back to bed.
This is a phrase that you're going to
hear parents say a lot to their children.
So if the children are awake or
walking around, you say get back to bed.
That means go back to sleep.
Go back to sleep.
That's right.
And we want the kid to go back to
sleep so we can let Santa do his job.
All right.
Like that last phrase, this is a
phrase that you can use in other ways.
It's not just for Christmas.
But we said, you know,
let Santa do his job.
Let Santa leave his presence.
Let's not bother Santa.
But we can change
Santa with any other name.
Right.
So you can say, I don't
know, maybe your dad
is working in the office and your mom
will tell you, you know, come out here.
Let dad do his job.
I mean, don't bother dad.
Don't distract him.
Let him work.
Right.
OK.
So that's the way that
you use those phrases.
Very good stuff here.
Why don't we review one last time?
What are you doing awake?
I can't sleep.
But it's almost midnight.
Exactly.
I'm too excited for Christmas morning.
Also, I thought I heard Santa.
Really?
How do you know it was Santa?
Well, I heard that naughty boys and
girls get cold and they're stockings.
So I thought I'd be nice
and make Santa cookies.
I even left out some milk.
I heard someone in the kitchen
eating the cookies so I came downstairs.
Hmm.
Well, I know that Santa
won't come down the
chimney with you hiding
behind the tree spying on him.
Really?
Let's go back upstairs and get back to bed.
That way we can let Santa do his job.
Then, when you wake up,
it will be Christmas already.
OK.
Hey, honey.
Is that you?
Don't eat all the cookies.
I want some too.
All right, so these
Christmas traditions are--
as we said, they're
typically American, but
many other cultures share
similar traditions like this.
That's correct.
So obviously, traditions
are different than
every family, not everyone
celebrates Christmas morning.
Some people celebrate Christmas Eve, but
most people will be familiar with Christmas
stockings, Christmas trees, and
Santa who comes down the chimney.
That's right.
So it also depends, I
guess, on the culture and
religion, some religions celebrate
Christmas differently or not at all.
So it's actually a very
interesting time of the year.
But if you look--
or if you can see any
American movies, like I
remember this one called
The Santa Claus, it's
very-- you can see the
typical American
Christmas, you know, snow,
and trees, and presents, and
Santa Claus, a lot of things.
That's right.
So a good way to end this, Avita,
say, have a very merry Christmas.
That means, you know, have
a nice holiday, enjoy Christmas.
If you're not going to
celebrate Christmas, for
whatever reason, you
can just say happy holidays.
Happy holidays.
That's right.
And, of course, you can
go to our website, www.
EnglishPod.com, where we
want to know if you celebrate
Christmas or what are the
Christmas traditions in your country.
That's right.
We're very curious to hear those.
So we'll see you soon
on www.EnglishPod.com.
All right.
We'll see you guys.
Bye.